<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio website for Anna Plaschke</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio website for Anna Plaschke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:42:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol Consumption by Country</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog6/</guid>
      <description>knitr::opts_chunk$set(message = FALSE, warning = FALSE, tidy=FALSE, # display code as typedsize=&amp;quot;small&amp;quot;) # slightly smaller font for codeoptions(digits = 3)# default figure sizeknitr::opts_chunk$set(fig.width=6.75, fig.height=6.75,fig.align = &amp;quot;center&amp;quot;)Where Do People Drink The Most Beer, Wine And Spirits?With this project I want to analyse how the consumption of alcohol of beer, wine and spirits variy by country.
Let’s first load the data: To load the dataset I use the package: Fivethirtyeight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anna Plaschke</title>
      <link>/post/post1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post1/</guid>
      <description>My biographyMy name is Anna Plaschke, I am 24 years old and I grew up in the German speaking region of Italy, South Tyrol. I went to the German speaking school Realgymnasium Bozen and did an exchange in the Italian counterpart-school, Liceo Scientifico Torricelli.
I graduated with honours in Business, Economics and Social Sciences from Vienna University of Economics and Business and did an exchange semester in Hongkong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HIV Rate, Life Expectancy, Fertility Rate and GDP</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog7/</guid>
      <description>HIV Rate, Life Expectancy and GDPThe purpose of this project is to analyze the relationship between HIV rate, life expectancy and GDP per capita by regions.
Loading, inspecting and joining datasetsLoading data
The first step, is to load the data: I load the gapminder HIV data and life expectancy data using read_csv to convert the csv files. The worldbank data instead is loaded from a package wbstats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is Getting Warm in Here!</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog5/</guid>
      <description>Climate change and temperature anomaliesThe whole world is talking about climate change and global warming. Let’s look at the data from Combined Land-Surface Air and Sea-Surface Water Temperature Anomalies in the Northern Hemisphere at NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies and analyse what the data states.
Loading, inspecting and selecting dataLoading dataAs first step, I load the data with the function read_csv().
#I use: data on the *Combined Land-Surface Air and Sea-Surface Water Temperature Anomalies* in the Northern Hemisphere at [NASA&amp;#39;s Goddard Institute for Space Studies](https://data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Expectancy, School enrollment, Fertility Rate and GDP</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog8/</guid>
      <description>Fertiliy Rate, School Entrollment, Life Expectancy and GDPThe purpose of this project is to analyze the relationship between school enrollment, fertility rate, life expectancy and GDP per capita by regions. In addition, I will look at the improvement of the mortality rate by region and by country between 1960 and 2016.
Loading, inspecting and joining datasetsLoading data
The first step, is to load the data: I load the gapminder life expectancy data using read_csv to convert the csv files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Expectancy, School enrollment, Fertility Rate and GDP</title>
      <link>/blogs/blog8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blogs/blog8/</guid>
      <description>Fertiliy Rate, School Entrollment, Life Expectancy and GDPThe purpose of this project is to analyze the relationship between school enrollment, fertility rate, life expectancy and GDP per capita by regions. In addition, I will look at the improvement of the mortality rate by region and by country between 1960 and 2016.
Loading, inspecting and joining datasetsLoading data
The first step, is to load the data: I load the worldbank data instead is loaded from the package wbstats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>